Quantum of Solace is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by Marc Forster.
Betrayed by Vesper, the woman he loved, 007 fights the
urge to make his latest mission personal.
Pursuing his determination to uncover the truth, Bond and M interrogate Mr.
White, who reveals that the organization that blackmailed Vesper is far
more complex and dangerous than anyone had imagined.
James Bond, played by Daniel Craig.
Camille, played by Olga Kurylenko.
Dominic Greene, played by Mathieu Amalric.
M, played by Judi Dench.
Mathis, played by Giancarlo Giannini.
Strawberry Fields, played by Gemma Arterton.
Quantum of Solace is a 2008 action spy film and the twenty-second in
the James Bond series produced by Eon Productions.
Directed by Marc Forster and written by Neal Purvis, Robert Wade, and Paul Haggis, it is the sequel to Casino
Royale (2006), and stars Daniel Craig in his second appearance as the fictional MI6 agent James Bond.
The film co-stars Olga Kurylenko, Mathieu Amalric, Giancarlo
Giannini, Jeffrey Wright, and Judi Dench.
In the film, Bond teams with Camille Montes (Kurylenko) to stop Dominic Greene
(Amalric) from monopolizing the Bolivian freshwater supply.
A second Bond film starring Craig was planned before
production began on Casino Royale in October 2005.
In July 2006, Roger Michell was announced to direct with a planned release for May
2008, but left the project that October after delays with the screenplay.
Purvis, Wade, and Haggis completed the screenplay by June 2007, after
which Forster was announced as Michell's replacement.
Craig and Forster also contributed uncredited rewrites to the film's screenplay.
Principal photography began in August 2007 and lasted until May 2008, with filming locations including Mexico,
Panama, Chile, Italy, Austria, and Wales, while interior sets were built and filmed at Pinewood Studios.
The film's title is borrowed from a 1959 short story by Ian Fleming.
In contrast to its predecessor, Quantum of Solace is notable for citing inspiration from early Bond film sets
designed by Ken Adam, while it features a departure from tropes associated with Bond villains.
Quantum of Solace premiered at the Odeon Leicester Square on 29 October 2008 and was theatrically
released first in the United Kingdom two days later and in the United States on 14 November.
The film received mixed reviews, with praise for Craig's performance and the
action sequences but was deemed inferior to its predecessor.
It grossed over $589 million worldwide, becoming the seventh highest-grossing film of 2008
and the fifth highest-grossing James Bond film, unadjusted for inflation.
The next film in the series, Skyfall, was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of undercover, spy, killing, secret agent, mi6.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.